chronogram.com 2014-11-29

# Privacy Policy | Hudson Valley; Chronogram

## information gathered by luminary publishing, Inc.

When you visit the Luminary Publishing, Inc.'s websites (www.Chronogram.com and www.HVHealthyLiving.com; henceforth referred to as "Luminary Publishing, Inc.'s websites") and interact with the services and tools that reside there, Luminary Publishing, Inc. and the third parties with whom we have contracted to provide services to Luminary Publishing, Inc. may collect information on your actions. This type of information is generally collected from two sources; from the server log files and from cookies. How we collect and disseminate information 

The information collected by Luminary Publishing, Inc. is used to create aggregated portraits of our audience, representing anonymous statistical demographic information but never personally identifiable information. This aggregated information is used, among other things, to determine trends and needs, and also to supply market research to potential advertisers and partners to help them understand whom the Luminary Publishing, Inc. audience is. For example, we may create a report indicating that 40 percent of our readers are married women with one or more children living in their household, so that potential advertisers and partners can determine which of their products or services are most appropriate for our readers. 

In order to better understand how we collect and disseminate information, please keep reading this document. 

## electronic newsletters

Luminary Publishing, Inc. offers free electronic newsletters on a variety of topics. If you choose to subscribe to any of our newsletters, currently the only information you will be required to provide is a valid email address. In order to receive these newsletters you must opt-in to receiving them. Generally, Luminary Publishing, Inc. does not share mailing lists from its electronic newsletters with third parties. However, in some situations, Luminary Publishing, Inc. may share its newsletter mailing lists with third parties who provide newsletter fulfillment services on our behalf. In these instances, such third parties will be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

## surveys and polls

Our surveys typically ask for demographic information (like zip code, age, gender, and other personal information). We may also seek your opinions on various issues and very often these surveys and polls are sponsored by or associated with Luminary Publishing, Inc. advertisers and partners. Most information obtained through surveys and polls is aggregated and used internally or shared with advertisers and partners only in the aggregated form. In the event personally identifiable information is requested as part of surveys or polls about any Luminary Publishing, Inc. reader, such personally identifiable information is never provided to third parties without your consent. In these instances you may expressly choose to receive information from a sponsor, in which case your information is provided to that sponsor only. 

## contests

Luminary Publishing, Inc occasionally has contests and giveaways for our readers. We typically ask you for your first and last names, email address and daytime phone number (to notify you if you've won). In some situations, we may need additional information as part of the entry process, such as a prize selection. This information is shared with a third party: When you choose to receive information from a third party contest sponsor; or when a contest is hosted by Luminary Publishing, Inc. but administered by a sponsor; we will advise you of this in the contest rules. 

You should carefully review the rules of each contest and giveaway which you enter as they may contain additional important information about Luminary Publishing, Inc.'s or a sponsor's use of your personal information. 

## links to advertiser, partner, and third-party sites

Luminary Publishing, Inc.'s websites contain links to advertiser, partner, and third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies or the content of non-Luminary Publishing, Inc. websites, and we do not control the practices of any of our advertisers or partners whose links appear on our websites. 

In any instance where personally identifiable information is required to be provided to or shared with Luminary Publishing, Inc.'s advertisers and partners, we will advise you when such advertiser or partner will receive your personal information, and further advise you as to which Privacy Policy will control the collection and dissemination of personally identifiable information you provide. Luminary Publishing, Inc. will use commercially reasonable efforts to contractually require all third party advertisers and partners to abide by the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

If you have additional questions about how one of our advertisers, partners or sponsors will use information about you, please contact them directly. 

## information we collect through ip address and cookies

Your IP address is a number that is assigned by your ISP (Internet Service Provider) to your computer to identify its location. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website. 

Our site uses a feature of your browser to set a "cookie" on your computer. Cookies are small packets of information that a site's server stores on your computer. The Luminary Publishing, Inc. websites can then read the cookies whenever you visit the Luminary Publishing, Inc. websites. These cookies allow us to use the information we collect to customize your Luminary Publishing, Inc. experience so that your visit to our websites is as relevant and as valuable to your interests as possible. 

Your browser preferences provide you with choices relating to cookies. You have the ability to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject cookies you may be unable to use those Luminary Publishing, Inc. services that require registration in order to participate or will have to re-register each time you visit the Luminary Publishing, Inc. websites. 

## information sharing policy

Luminary Publishing, Inc. does not sell or otherwise share personally identifiable information with third parties without your consent except in the following instances: (i) if required by applicable law or pursuant to a court or similar order; (ii) as deemed necessary, in Luminary Publishing, Inc.'s discretion, to protect the legal rights or the property of Luminary Publishing, Inc., a member or third party, or to prevent personal injury; and/or (iii) in the event that Luminary Publishing, Inc. is required to transfer personally identifiable information to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, assignment, joint venture, or other transfer or disposition of a portion or all of the assets or stock of Luminary Publishing, Inc. or its affiliated entities (including, without limitation, in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings). In addition, Luminary Publishing, Inc. reserves the right to allow access to its systems to third parties providing necessary technical services when such access is required in order to provide those services and to provide your personal information to third parties who provide services on our behalf, provided that such third parties are bound by Luminary Publishing, Inc.'s Privacy Policy. Please note, however, that Luminary Publishing, Inc. reserves the right to share any personally identifiable or other information about you which you provide to (or which is gathered by) the Luminary Publishing, Inc. websites with any or all of its subsidiaries and affiliates and will also have access to any such information which you provide to (or which is gathered by) the websites of any Luminary Publishing, Inc. subsidiary or affiliate. 

## how we protect and secure your information

Luminary Publishing, Inc. has numerous security measures in place to protect you from the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control, including your credit card information if you choose to conduct an e-commerce transaction on the Luminary Publishing, Inc. websites. 

Luminary Publishing, Inc. uses industry-standard tools, such as firewalls, to ensure that your information is secure and confidential. 

## protection regarding children

The concern for safeguarding children on the Internet is something we take seriously at Luminary Publishing, Inc. We realize that some of our content may not be appropriate for all children. Luminary Publishing, Inc. does not encourage unsupervised visitation to our websites by children. 

## contact information

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or anything else about Luminary Publishing, Inc., you can contact us at the following email address: info@chronogram.com. We look forward to the opportunity to address your concerns. 

## delivery and refund policy

All sales are Final.  Subscriptions are sent out on the 26th day of each month via US Mail.
